CRYSTAL SHEELEY

WEB DEVELOPER



Contact



San Diego, CA Willing to relocate



+213-649-8796



Portfolio

https://crystal-sheeley-portfolio.netlify.app



crystal.sheeley13@gmail.com

Skills

Project Management

Problem Solving

Technical Training:

- HTML5
- CSS3
- JavaScript
 - o Node.js
 - React.js
- Python
- Express
- Github
- SQL/noSQL

Education

General Assembly, 2022-2023

Software Engineering Immersive

Duquesne University, 2012

Bachelor of Arts Modern Languages | English Literature

About Me

I am a newly qualified Software Engineer from General Assembly's Bootcamp Software Engineering Immersive where I built full-stack web applications. With 7 years experience in project management and teaching, I was able to apply my ability to learn new technologies, design efficient workflows, and implement creative problem-solving in a fast-paced environment. I am looking for a role developing web-based applications.

B Relevant Work Experience

Software Engineering Apprentice

November 2022- February 2023

General Assembly Bootcamp

Completed a 420-hour Software Engineering Immersive bootcamp learning full-stack development.

- Project 1: Designed and created a crawler game using vanilla
 Javascript, Canvas, HTML and CSS demonstrating basic principles in
 action
- Project 2: Designed a personal project management tool using Express, Node.js, SQL, and Bootstrap to integrate databases and frontend frameworks.
- Project 3: Working with a team, we created a food delivery app using React, Express, and MongoDB to practice user authentication and Git workflows.
- Project 4: Designed and programmed a full-stack MERN web application complete with user authentication. Features include payments via Stripe, and browsing movies for rental.

Systems Trainer (contract) Administrative Support (contract)

May 2019 - September 2019

Ministry for Primary Industries, New Zealand

Trained government employees in the use of a fit-for-purpose software built from Salesforce.

- Learned and implemented new software systems to prepare for training seminars
- Refined data for migration, and assisted in data migration.

Senior Coordinator of Campaigns

March 2015-October 2016

Points of Light, New York, NY

Responsible for grant disbursement, building marketing content, and analyzing incoming data for strategic planning in a national nonprofit dedicated to youth activism.

- Managed 7 campaign cycles by building marketing campaigns and analyzing data for strategic planning.
- Tracked, coordinated, and reported on the implementation of more than 200 grantees volunteer projects.
- Created the marketing plan, content for webpages, and maintenance of website for all program areas.

Work Experience

Project Coordinator

November 2013 - April 2015

Iva Kaufman Associates, New York, NY,

Coordinated the projects of a boutique agency dedicated to finding funding for environmental projects, social entrepreneurs, and the arts.

- · Organized projects, contracts, and set funding goals.
- Coordinated newsletter marketing and fundraising campaigns.
- Solicited small to medium sized business with a focus on sustainability for the non-profit, American Sustainable Business Council (ASBC) to: recruit new members, promote community events, and provide marketing support for political advocacy campaigns.

Content Manager

January 2014 - March 2015

TheBarnYardGroup, Stamford, CT

Organized marketing plans, created content, and collaborated with thought-leaders in education and women's economic empowerment to promote events.

- Wrote press releases, proposals, reports and case histories.
- · Monitored program budgets and costs to create the most effective campaigns for each client.
- Collaborated with team members to provide social media outreach for multiple campaigns while branding social good initiatives.
- Worked on campaigns for foodtweeks (social impact app), PowerShift 2014 (Women and Finance Forum), S.H.E. Summit (Women's Leadership Conference), The New York International School.

Teaching Experience

Homeroom Teacher, Kindergarten

June 2021 - July 2022

Hillside Collegiate Jr., Busan, South Korea

Taught homeroom in an international school based on Common Core standards.

- Designed and executed lessons for six and seven year old learners with a hands-on approach to both social and educational materials.
- Created a variety of teaching materials to accommodate different learning styles.
- Provided extensive individual feedback for student evaluation.
- Prepared extra-curricular activities and monitored field trips for students.

English as a Foreign Language Teacher

June 2018 - November 2018

VUS, Hanoi, Vietnam

Led learners from age 6 to adult in classroom activities to promote language learning.

- Created learning materials and lesson plans based on age group and learning style.
- Conducted placement tests for incoming students and implemented testing for class progress and evaluation.

English as a Foreign Language Teacher

November 2016 - April 2018

Viewhigh Language Institute, Geoje, South Korea

Conducted lessons encompassing a range of skill building activities in the four areas of language learning: Speaking, Writing, Reading, and Listening.

- · Delivered engaging and informative lessons on English grammar, spelling, vocabulary, and pronunciation
- · Carefully selected and organized course materials for each group of students.
- · Continually explore and incorporate new teaching methods, strategies, and activities.